Aravindh M

Senior Engineer

Address Chennai, India 600062

Phone 7397406203

E-mail aravindhm33@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/aravindh-m-a4a685148

Senior full stack web developer specializing in front end development. Experienced with all stages of the web development cycle of dynamic and responsive web application projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML, JavaScript, Angular and springBoot.

Work History

2022-06 - Current

Senior Engineer

Mindtree Ltd, Chennai

- Involved in UI development of registration cloud migration project.
- Understood client requirements and developed as per wireframes.
- Migrated existing Angular 10 application to Angular 13.
- Made sure that application is ADA complaint and responsive across different devices/browsers.
- Worked on email domain regex change across multiple application as per new business requirement.
- Developed code without any dependency vulnerability and lint issues.
- Reviewed my code with leads to make sure development is as per UI standards.
- Identified existing prod issues and fixed issues after business approval.
- Responsible for setting up UI environment for new joiners in their local.

2021-03 - 2021-06

Engineer

Mindtree Ltd, Chennai

- Joined as fresher in client project to learn UI standards.
- Involved in development of independent reusable components to be used in multiple applications.
- Wrote unit test cases for all multiple applications using jasmine and maintained 80% coverage.
- Migrated from questionnaire based user verification system to mobile/telephone based user verification using reusable code across multiple applications.
- Implemented analytics for events invoked from UI.

Education

2016-06 - 2020-09 B.E: Computer Science And Engineering

Panimalar Engineering College - Chennai, India Completed U.G Programme with 8.32 CGPA

2014-06 - 2016-05 Higher Secondary School

Velammal Matriculation Higher Secondary School - Chennai, India Completed Higher Secondary School with 94.08%.

Skills

- Angular
- JavaScript
- HTML, CSS
- Java
- SpringBoot

- MySQL
- Python
- React JS

Projects and Research

GST Calculator using Python and SQL

• Implemented console based GST Calculator for business purpose using Python and SQL for database.

Tic-Tac-Toe

Developed a console based Tic-Tac-Toe game using python for two users.

Diabetic Guidance System

- Proposed a web app for diabetic patient to monitor their blood glucose level.
- Worked along with the team to develop the web app using MERN stack.

Mobility in Snowbound Area - DRUSE DRDO

- Research along with the team to propose an idea for mobility in snow area for DRDO - India.
- Prepared a demo model for zonal level Competition.

Certifications and Awards

- "A-Team award", by Mindtree Ltd. Total of 3 awards under this category for successful delivery as a team on various requirements.
- "Optimism award", by TECH LEAD at Mindtree Ltd as a recognition for my angular skills.
- Completed a crash course on Angular, Node JS Interactive in Plural sight.
- Completed basic and Intermediate Angular Assessment from Hackerrank.